Yury Voloshin

186 Bay 26th St., Apt 3A, Brooklyn, NY 11214 (917) 349-8135 yvoloshino1@gmail.com

WEB DEVELOPER

My background blends the hands-on experience in web development and software development with the problem-solving and analytical mindset developed as a Ph.D.-level chemical engineer to offer solid skills in web application building, as well as systematic testing and debugging approaches.

Languages: Ruby, Javascript, C#, HTML, CSS

Tools: Ruby on Rails, jQuery, Twitter Bootstrap, Git, GitHub, Heroku, Amazon Web Services, Redis, Pry,

Travis CI

Github profile: https://github.com/yvoloshin

EXPERIENCE

The Firehose Project

Full-Stack Web Development Apprentice

5/2015 - 8/2015

- Developed Ruby on Rails applications using a test-driven approach and RESTful architectures both on an individual basis and as part of a team of developers
- Actively developed and contributed to a group project as part of a remote team by sharing code through Github and communicating with the team using Slack and Trello
- Backend: set up postgreSQL databases, user authentication, and version control through Git / Github
- Frontend: used CSS / HTML, Javascript, jQuery, Twitter Bootstrap to build responsive websites

Gerson Lehrman Group, Inc., New York, NY

Consultant

8/2014 - 5/2015

• Consulted on various aspects of catalysis-related projects

BASF Catalysts Inc., Iselin, NJ

Research Engineer

7/2008 - 7/2014

- Designed and developed software for calculating pressure drop across catalytic converters using C# and continuously improved it through several releases, which became a widely-used tool throughout BASF
- Created mathematical models of automotive catalytic converters by analyzing experimental data and used the models to optimize emission abatement systems, thus decreasing the need for much more expensive full-scale engine tests
- Decreased the downtime of an automated reactor system by 20% by reducing operational inefficiencies
- Designed and performed experiments to obtain data for models of catalytic converters
- Other duties: internal auditor for ISO/TS16949 standard, safety inspector, Certified First Responder and member of First Aid Team

Yury Voloshin – Page Two (917) 349-8135 | yvoloshino1@gmail.com

Stevens Institute of Technology, Hoboken, NJ

Ph. D. Candidate / Graduate Research Assistant

5/2004 - 5/2008

- Developed a novel lab-scale process for production of hydrogen peroxide from hydrogen and oxygen
- Created a mathematical model of the hydrogen peroxide process by analyzing experimental data
- Award: Robert C. Stanley Graduate Fellowship in Engineering and Science

Teaching Assistant

9/2001 - 5/2004

- Supervised students and presented lectures in Materials Science Lab
- Tutored students for undergraduate chemical engineering courses

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Web Development, Algorithm, and Data Structures Foundations - Firehose Project (5/2015 – 8/2015)

- Learned how to build-out basic CRUD Rails apps following standard Rails conventions (without using scaffolding), involving mailers, validations, image uploading on AWS S3 and nested RESTful routes
- Implemented tests using the MiniTest's Test::Unit syntax for both unit and functional tests
- Worked through traditional computer science algorithms and data structures challenges
- Pair programmed with senior web developers as well as with peers

MyRecipeBox https://allmyrecipes.herokuapp.com Personal Project Ongoing Application for storing and displaying recipes (Ruby on Rails, Postgresql, Heroku, Sass)

- Conceptualized and wireframed the app
- Developed a system for displaying one's recipes and sharing them with others

EDUCATION

Stevens Institute of Technology, Hoboken, NJ Ph.D. in Chemical Engineering, 2008 Bachelor of Engineering in Chemical Engineering, 2000

New York University, New York, NY **Bachelor of Science in Chemistry,** 2000

Foreign Languages: Russian (fluent)

Other Activities: food blogger (bystroblog.wordpress.com) and author of a cookbook

(myBook.to/cookbook)